<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="nama_daerah">Regional Name</string>
    <string name="detail">Detail</string>
    <string name="tentang_aplikasi">About Application</string>
    <string name="tentangapp">The ATLAS INDONESIA application is a simple application developed by ARIF PURNOMO AJI (Codename: Reefii) which contains content about the map of the Indonesian region. If there are suggestions/feedback for further application development, you can contact the developer via Email: Arifpurnomoaji998@gmail.com, or by pressing the developer contact button below:</string>
    <string name="pengaturan">Language Settings</string>
    <string name="pustaka">Library Resources</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="unduh_buku_atlas_indonesia">Download Atlas Indonesia Book</string>
    <string name="sumber_1">This app is made based on data from the Official Ebook:</string>
    <string name="sumber_3">from the Indonesian Geospatial Information Agency (BIG), which can be accessed via the button below</string>
    <string name="detail_derah">Detail Information</string>
    <string name="uraian_detail_daerah">Regional Details</string>
    <string name="daerah_ini">Hello, I found details regarding the area</string>
    <string name="peta_area">REGION MAP</string>
    <string name="cubitklik">(pinch or click to enlarge map)</string>
    <string name="pengaturanmain">Settings</string>


    <!--description-->
    <string name="des_NKRI">Indonesia, also known as the Unitary State of the Republic of Indonesia (NKRI, Indonesian pronunciation: [nə\ˈɡara kəsa\ˈt̪ua̯n re\ˈpublɪk in.\ˈdo.nɛ.sja]); or simply the Republic of Indonesia (RI) is a country in Southeast Asia which is crossed by the equator and is located between the mainland of the Asian and Australian continents, as well as between the Pacific Ocean and the Indian Ocean. Indonesia is the largest archipelagic country in the world consisting of 17,504 islands.[15] The alternative name commonly used is Nusantara.[16] With a population of 270,203,917 in 2020,[17] Indonesia is the fourth most populous country in the world and the most populous Muslim country in the world, with more than 230 million followers. The form of the Indonesian state is unitary and the form of government of Indonesia is a republic, with the House of Representatives, the Regional Representative Council and the President who are directly elected. The capital city of Indonesia is Jakarta. Indonesia lands with Malaysia on the island of Borneo and Sebatik Island, with Papua New Guinea on the island of Papua and with Timor Leste on the island of Timor. Other neighboring countries are Singapore, the Philippines, Australia, and the union territory of the Andaman and Nicobar Islands in India. The number of islands in Indonesia (including large and small islands) as stated in Law No. 6 of 1996 concerning Indonesian Waters is 17,508 islands, but there are problems of effective occupation in 4 islands, namely Sipadan Island, Ligitan Island, Yako Island and Kambing Island. lead to the loss of ownership of the island. To prevent this from happening again, the Government of the Republic of Indonesia has taken many actions and at the borders, especially in the Small Islands and the Outermost Small Islands. Indonesia has 111 Outermost Small Islands which have been stipulated in Presidential Decree 6/2017 concerning Designation of Outermost Small Islands. In Indonesia, there are 5 major islands including Sumatra Island, Java Island, Kalimantan Island, Sulawesi Island and Papua Island.</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUSUMATRA">Quoted in the book \'Let\'s Get to Know Indonesia: Sumatra 1\' by Munasifah, the total area of ​​Sumatra Island is 473,600 square kilometers, almost the size of Great Britain. To the west lies the Indian Ocean; in the eastern and southeastern parts of the Malacca Strait, Karimata Strait, and the Java Sea; while in the southern part stretches the Sunda Strait. The shape of the island of Sumatra extends from Ulee Lheue in the north to Tanjung China in the south, along about 1,650 kilometers. Its width in the north is between 100 and 200 kilometers, while the width of the southern part is about 350 kilometers. Its two largest bays are Watermelon and Lampung in Lampung Province. Administratively, the territory is divided into one special region (Aceh) and 9 provinces (North Sumatra, West Sumatra, Bengkulu, Riau, Riau Islands, Jambi, South Sumatra, Lampung, Bangka Belitung Islands).</string>
    <string name="des_ACEH">Aceh was inaugurated as a province on December 7, 1959. It has an area of ​​57,956.00 sq km. Currently there are 5,371,532 residents occupying the province of Aceh. The capital city of Aceh province is Banda Aceh. The religion of the Acehnese is Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_SUMATRAUTARA">North Sumatra was inaugurated by the government for the first time on November 29, 1956. This province has an area of ​​72,981.23 square km with a population of 15,851,851 people, the majority of whom are Muslims. North Sumatra is the province with the most population in Indonesia which ranks fourth. The capital city of North Sumatra is the city of Medan.</string>
    <string name="des_SUMATRASELATAN">South Sumatra was inaugurated by the government for the first time on August 14, 1960. Jambi Province has an area of ​​91,592.43 km2 with a population of 7,941,500, the largest being Muslim. The capital of the province, which is located in the southern part of the island of Sumatra, has the city of Palembang as its capital.</string>
    <string name="des_SUMATRABARAT">West Sumatra was inaugurated by the government for the first time on August 9, 1957. This province has an area of ​​42,012.89 sq km with a population of 5,131,900 people, the majority of whom are Muslims. The city of Padang as the largest city in the western part of Sumatra Island is the capital of this province. The city of Padang is the gateway to the Indonesian state from the Indian Ocean.</string>
    <string name="des_BENGKULU">This province in Sumatra was first inaugurated as a province on November 18, 1968. Bengkulu Province has a capital city of the same name, Bengkulu. The province, which has an area of ​​19,919.33 sq km, enjoys 1,884,800 people by embracing Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_RIAU">Riau Province has the city of Pekanbaru as its capital. The province, which was born on August 9, 1957, is located in the central part of the East coast of the Sumatran archipelago. The population of Riau province as much as 60% adheres to Islam. Riau Province has an area of ​​50,058.16 sq km with a population of 3,344,400 people.</string>
    <string name="des_KEP.RIAU">Riau Archipelago Province is an Indonesian province bordering North Cambodia and Vietnam. Riau Islands Province has the city of Tanjungpinang as its capital. This province was first inaugurated by the government on October 25, 2002. The population of the Riau Islands is 1,917,415 people, with the majority embracing Islam. Riau Archipelago has an area of ​​8,201.72 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_JAMBI">Jambi Province has a capital city with the same name as the province, namely Jambi. It was first inaugurated by the government on August 9, 1957. Jambi Province has an area of ​​50,058.16 square kilometers with a population of 3,344,400 people. 65% of the population of Jambi Province adheres to Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_LAMPUNG">Lampung was born on March 18, 1964. This province, which is located in the southern part of Sumatra Island, has a capital city of Bandar Lampung. Lampung Province has two cities, Bandar Lampung City and Metro City. Lampung Province has an area of ​​34,623.80 sq km with a population of 8,026,191 people. The majority of the population of Lampung embraces Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_BANGKABELITUNG">The Bangka Belitung Islands were inaugurated on November 21, 2000. It has an area of ​​16,424.05 sq km with a population of 1,343,900 people. The capital of Bangka Belitung is Pangkalpinang. Half the population of Bangka Belitung embraces Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUKALIMANTAN">The island, which is still mostly forested and a habitat for a number of endemic plants and animals, has an area of ​​about 743,330 square km. The island of Borneo has a maritime boundary in the west with the Karimata Strait, in the east with the Makassar Strait, in the south with the Java Sea, and in the north with the South China Sea.</string>
    <string name="des_KALIMANTANBARAT">Pontianak City is the capital city of West Kalimantan Province. West Kalimantan was first inaugurated as a province by the government on December 7, 1956. The province, which is located in the west of the island of Kalimantan, has an area of ​​147,307.00 sq km which is occupied by as many as 4,716,093 people. Half the population of West Kalimantan adheres to Islam. West Kalimantan is ranked fourth as the largest province in Indonesia.</string>
    <string name="des_KALIMANTANTIMUR">East Kalimantan is a province of Indonesia which borders with Malaysia. The capital city of East Kalimantan Province is Samarinda. It was first inaugurated by the Government on July 2, 1958. East Kalimantan has an area of ​​129,066.64 km2 with a population of 3,351,432, most of whom embrace Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_KALIMANTANSELATAN">South Kalimantan Province was born on December 7, 1956. South Kalimantan has a population of 3,922,790 with an area of ​​38,744.23 square kilometers. 98% of the population of the province of South Kalimantan embraces Islam. The province of South Kalimantan has the city of Banjarmasin as its capital.</string>
    <string name="des_KALIMANTANTENGAH">Palangkaraya is the capital of the province of Central Kalimantan. Central Kalimantan was first inaugurated as a province on July 2, 1958. This province has an area of ​​153,564.50 which is occupied by as many as 2,439,858 people. Most of Central Kalimantan\'s population adheres to Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_KALIMANTANUTARA">North Kalimantan (abbreviated as Kaltara) is a province in Indonesia located in the northern part of the island of Borneo. This province is directly adjacent to neighboring Malaysia, namely the states of Sabah and Sarawak. The administrative center of North Kalimantan is currently located in Tanjung Selor City, along with the administrative center of Bulungan Regency. This province has an area of ​​75,467.70 km2 with a population of 688,426 people</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUJAWA">Although it is the main pillar of economic cycle in Indonesia, the area of ​​Java is not the largest in Indonesia. Based on the map, the island of Java is estimated at 128,297 km² with six provinces and small islands around it. The provinces on the island of Java are DKI Jakarta, West Java, Central Java, DI Yogyakarta, East Java, and Banten. The northern boundary is the Java Sea and the island of Borneo, the southern boundary is the Indian Ocean, the western boundary is the island of Sumatra, and the eastern boundary is the island of Bali. Meanwhile, the northern boundary is the Java Sea, the southern boundary is the Indian Ocean, the western boundary is the Sunda Strait, and the eastern boundary is the Bali Strait.</string>
    <string name="des_BANTEN">Banten is a province which has the capital city of Serang. Banten Province has a population of 11,704,877 people with the majority being Muslim. This province was inaugurated by the Government on October 4, 2000. Banteng Province has an area of ​​9,662.92 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_DKI.JAKARTA">The Special Capital Region of Jakarta is the capital city of Indonesia. The city of Jakarta is a city that is at the same level as the province. Jakarta is the largest city in Indonesia. The capital city of Jakarta was born on August 28, 1961. This province has an area of ​​664.01 sq km with 10,012,271 inhabitants occupying the capital city of Jakarta.</string>
    <string name="des_JAWABARAT">The capital city of West Java Province is the city of Bandung which is the largest metropolitan city in West Java Province. West Java Province was first inaugurated on July 4, 1950. The population in West Java is 48,274,162 people and the majority follow Islam. West Java Province has an area of ​​35,377.76 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_JAWATENGAH">Central Java province was inaugurated by the government as a province on the ladder; March 4, 1950. Central Java has Semarang as its capital. Central Java province is occupied by 3,553,100 residents with an area of ​​3,133.15 sq km. 85% of the population of Central Java province embraces Islam</string>
    <string name="des_DI.YOGYAKARTA">The Special Region of Yogyakarta is a fusion of the State of the Sultanate of Yogyakarta and the Duchy of Paku Alaman. The province, which is located in the southern part of Java Island, was first inaugurated by the government on March 4, 1950. The Special Region of Yogyakarta has a population of 3,553,100, with the majority being Muslims. This province in Java has an area of ​​3,133.15 sq km. The city of Yogyakarta is the center of government as well as the capital of the province of the Special Region of Yogyakarta. In addition, the city of Yogyakarta is one of the largest cities in Indonesia.</string>
    <string name="des_JAWATIMUR">The capital city of East Java Province is Surabaya. The province of East Java was first inaugurated on July 4, 1950. The population in East Java is 38,610,202 people and the majority follow Islam. East Java Province has an area of ​​37,799.75 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUBALIdanNT">The Nusa Tenggara Islands or the Lesser Sunda Islands[1] (now sometimes used in geographical maps of the world), are a group of islands to the east of Java Island, from Bali Island in the west, to Timor Island in the east.[2 ] The Southwest Islands and the Tanimbar Islands which are part of the geologically part of the Maluku Province are also included in the Nusa Tenggara islands. Administratively, most of the Nusa Tenggara Islands are part of the territory of Indonesia, except for the eastern part of the island of Timor and the surrounding small islands which are part of the territory of the state of Timor Leste. At the beginning of Indonesia\'s independence, the archipelago was a single province called the Lesser Sunda Province which changed its name to Nusa Tenggara Province in 1954,[3] which has a capital city of Singaraja. In 1975, the eastern tip of the Nusa Tenggara Islands in the eastern part of Timor Island was integrated into the Indonesian state to become the Province of East Timor until it gained its independence in 2002. The archipelago now consists of 3 provinces in Indonesia (from the west in succession): Bali; West Nusa Tenggara; and East Nusa Tenggara, as well as the 13 districts belonging to the state of Timor Leste.</string>
    <string name="des_BALI">Bali Province has a capital city called Denpasar. Bali was inaugurated as a province on August 14, 1958. Currently, the population in Bali Province is 4,104,900 people with an area of ​​5,780.06 sq km. The majority of the Balinese population embraces Hinduism.</string>
    <string name="des_NUSATENGGARATIMUR">East Nusa Tenggara is occupied by a population of 5,325,566 people with the majority embracing Christianity. The capital city of East Nusa Tenggara Province is the city of Kupang. East Nusa Tenggara has 22 regencies/cities with a total area of ​​48,718.10 sq km. This province in the Nusa Tenggara archipelago was first inaugurated on August 14, 1958.</string>
    <string name="des_NUSATENGGARABARAT">West Nusa Tenggara is occupied by a population of 4,773,795 people with the majority embracing Islam. The capital city of West Nusa Tenggara Province is the city of Mataram. West Nusa Tenggara has 12 regencies/cities with a total area of ​​18,572.32 sq km. This province in the Nusa Tenggara archipelago was first inaugurated on August 14, 1958.</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUSULAWESI">Sulawesi Island has an area of ​​174,600 km². With this area, there are six provinces that stand in it, namely South Sulawesi, Central Sulawesi, Southeast Sulawesi, North Sulawesi, West Sulawesi, and Gorontalo. Based on data from the Central Statistics Agency (BPS) released in 2018, the population on Sulawesi Island reached 19 million people. This figure comes from the provinces of South Sulawesi as many as 8.8 million, Central Sulawesi 3 million, Southeast Sulawesi 2.6 million, North Sulawesi 2.4 million, West Sulawesi 1.3 million, and Gorontalo as much as 1.1 million.</string>
    <string name="des_GORONTALO">Gorontalo Province is occupied by 1,115,633 people and has an area of ​​11,257.07 sq km. Gorontalo has a capital city with the same name, namely the city of Gorontalo. This province has the nickname Veranda of Medina with the majority of the population embracing Islam. Gorontalo Province was born on December 22, 2000.</string>
    <string name="des_SULAWESIBARAT">The province, which is located in the western part of the island of Sulawesi, was first inaugurated by the government as the 33rd province of Indonesia on October 5, 2004. The province of West Sulawesi has the city of Mamuju as its capital. The province, which has an area of ​​16,787.18 square kilometers, is occupied by 1,258,090 people, with the majority embracing Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_SULAWESISELATAN">The province of South Sulawesi was first inaugurated as a province on December 13, 1960. The province, which is located in the southern part of the island of Sulawesi, has the city of Makassar as its capital and administrative center. South Sulawesi Province has a population of 8,432,163 people, the majority of whom are Muslim. South Sulawesi Province has an area of ​​46,717.48 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_SULAWESIUTARA">North Sulawesi Province was born on December 13, 1960. The province, which is located in the northern part of the island of Sulawesi, has the city of Manado as its capital. The province which borders the Maluku Sea and the Pacific Ocean has a population of 2,386,604 people, the majority of whom are Christians. North Sulawesi Province has an area of ​​13,851.64 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_SULAWESITENGAH">Central Sulawesi was first inaugurated as a province on September 23, 1964. The capital city of Central Sulawesi Province is Palu City. Occupied by 2,831,283 residents, the majority of the population of Central Sulawesi adheres to Islam. Central Sulawesi is one of the provinces that has the largest area among other provinces on the island of Sulawesi with an area of ​​61,841.29 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_SULAWESITENGGARA">The province, which is located in the southeastern part of the island of Sulawesi, was first inaugurated by the government as a province on September 23, 1964. Southeast Sulawesi Province has the capital city of Kendari. The province which has an area of ​​39,067.70 sq km is occupied by as many as 2,448,081 people with the majority embracing Islam.</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUMALUKU">The Maluku Islands are a group of islands in Indonesia that are part of the archipelago. The Maluku Islands are located on the Eurasian and Pacific plates. It is bordered by Sulawesi Island to the west, New Guinea to the east, and Timor Leste to the south, Palau to the northeast. In ancient times, Europeans called it the "Spice Islands" — this term also refers to the Zanzibar Islands located on the coast of East Africa. From 1950 – 1999, the North Maluku Islands were administratively part of the Maluku Province. North Maluku Regency was later designated as North Maluku Province.</string>
    <string name="des_MALUKUUTARA">North Maluku (abbreviated as Malut) is a province in the eastern part of Indonesia which was officially formed on October 4, 1999 which previously became a district of the Maluku Province along with Central Halmahera, based on RI Law No. 46 of 1999 and RI Law No. 2003. The population of North Maluku in 2020 reached 1,305,828 people, with a population density of 41 people/km2. At the beginning of the establishment of North Maluku Province, the capital city was placed in Ternate City located at the foot of Mount Gamalama in a period of approximately 11 years, until on August 4, 2010 after a transition period and preparation for development, North Maluku moved the capital of North Maluku to Sofifi, one of the village in North Oba, the city of Tidore Islands. Sofifi Village is located on Halmahera Island, the largest island in North Maluku.</string>
    <string name="des_MALUKU">Maluku has the city of Ambon as its capital. Maluku Province is located between the borders of the Seram Sea and the Indian Ocean. The province, which is located in the southern part of the Maluku Islands, has an area of ​​46,914.03 square km with a population of 1,675,409 people, most of whom adhere to Christianity. Maluku Province was first inaugurated by the government on June 17, 1958.</string>
    <string name="des_PULAUPAPUA">The area of ​​the island of Papua is recorded at 786,000 km², but that which is part of Indonesia is only 418,707.7 km². While the rest is part of Papua New Guinea. This island is one of the 5 largest islands in the world. According to the book Ecology of Papua by the Indonesian Obor Library Foundation and Conservation International, the area of ​​Papua is an island that supports the largest ancient tropical forest that still exists in the Asia Pacific. In the westernmost part, Papua is dominated by small mountain ranges (Bird\'s Head, Wandamen, Fakfak, Kumawa) and islands (Raja Ampat, Teluk Cenderawasih). In many ways, Papua is similar to mainland Papua New Guinea (PNG) but the mountains are higher (reaching the snow line), the swamps are wider (eg, Mamberamo, Asmat). Papua Island is a habitat for 15,000–20,000 plant species (55% endemic), 602 bird species (52% endemic), 125 mammal species (58% endemic), and 223 reptile species (35% endemic). These endemic animals and plants include birds of paradise, tree kangaroos, rainbow fish, various butterflies and thousands of other plants and animals.</string>
    <string name="des_PAPUABARAT">West Papua Province covers the Domberai Peninsula and the Raja Ampat Islands. West Papua Province has a capital city which is located in the city of Manokwari and has the city of Sorong as the largest city in West Papua. West Papua Province has a population of 849,809 with the majority being Christian. The capital city of Papua Province is the city of Jayapura. The province, which was born on October 4, 1999, has an area of ​​6,570.74 sq km.</string>
    <string name="des_PAPUA">Papua Province originally had the name Irian Jaya. The eastern part of the Papua Province is the state of Papua New Guinea. Papua Province has a population of 3,091,047 with the majority being Christian. The capital city of Papua Province is the city of Jayapura. The province, which was born on September 10, 1969, has an area of ​​319,036.05 sq km.</string>
    <string name="diaplikasi">in Atlas Indonesia Aplication!</string>
    <string name="pengaturantema">Theme Setting</string>
    <string name="cubitin">(pinch by two fingers to enlarge map)</string>
    <string name="exit">Please click BACK again to exit</string>


</resources>